Guide to Records of the Office of the President (John Brademas) RG.3.0.10
New York University Archives
- Series XIII. Speeches and Writings, 1981-1991; 22.50 Linear Feet in 54 manuscript boxes.; 1 audiocassette; 3 VHS
  - Awarding Honorary Degrees to Stella Adler, Joan Ganz Cooney, Gianluigi Colalucci, Judith Ann Jamison, Victor Frederick, and Others (NYU), 1991-05-16 (Box 305, Folder 3)
  - Scripts for Brademas and Laurence Tisch, 159th Commencement (NYU), 1991-05-16 (Box 305, Folder 4-5)
  - Medical School Last Day Exercises (NYU), 1991-05-16 (Box 305, Folder 6)
  - Pancyprian Association Freedom Award Ceremony, Presented to George Paraskevaides (New York, NY), 1991-05-18 (Box 305, Folder 7)
  - American Association of Museums 86th Annual Meeting (Denver, CO), 1991-05-20 (Box 305, Folder 8)
  - Dinner Celebrating the Department of Dermatology (NYU), 1991-05-21 (Box 305, Folder 9)
  - President's Council Reception (NYU), 1991-05-21 (Box 305, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Commemorating the 125th Anniversary of the College of Dentistry (NYU), 1991-05-22 (Box 305, Folder 11)
  - "Key to the 21st Century: Educated Men & Women," Special Lecture at the University of Thessaloniki (Thessaloniki, Greece), 1991-05-30 (Box 305, Folder 12)
  - "Higher Education: The Global Perspective," Wolfson College Symposium on Higher Education (Oxford, England), 1991-06-07 (Box 305, Folder 13)
  - Introduction of President-Elect of the Russian Federation Boris Yeltsin (NYU), 1991-06-21 (Box 305, Folder 14)
  - Testimony Before a U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Education and Labor Hearing (NYU), 1991-06-24 (Box 305, Folder 15)
  - Brademas Receiving the National Society of Fund Raising Executives (NSFRE) Award for Achievement in Philanthropy (New York, NY), 1991-06-28 (Box 305, Folder 16)
  - Message to the School of Law, 1991-07-01 (Box 305, Folder 17)
  - "Education and The Environmental Crisis," International Conference on the Environment at the University of Barcelona (Barcelona, Spain), 1991-07-09 (Box 305, Folder 18)
  - Brademas Receipt of 1991 James G. O'Hara Education Leadership Award, Committee on Education Funding (Washington, D.C.), 1991-09-23 (Box 305, Folder 19)
- Series XIV. Correspondence, 1981-1990; 1983-1986; 3.30 Linear Feet in 8 manuscript boxes.
  This series contains chronological correspondence files dating from 1981 to 1990, with the bulk from 1983 to 1986. Topics include communications with staff and faculty; discussions with politicians and heads of state; relations with potential and existing donors; and parents requesting intervention for admission.
  - A -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 1)
  - Ba-Bn -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 2)
  - Bo-Bz -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 3)
  - C -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 4)
  - D -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 5)
  - E -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 6)
  - F -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 7)
  - G -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 8)
  - H -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 246, Folder 9)
  - I -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 1)
  - J -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 2)
  - K -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 3)
  - L -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 4)
  - Ma-Md -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 5)
  - Me-Mz -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 6)
  - N -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 7)
  - O -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 8)
  - P -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 247, Folder 9)
  - Q -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 1)
  - R -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 2)
  - Sa-Sh -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 3)
  - Si-Sz -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 4)
  - T -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 5)
  - U -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 6)
  - V -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 7)
  - W -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 8)
  - XYZ -- Alphabetical File, 1985-1986 (Box 248, Folder 9)
  - July, 1985 (Box 253, Folder 1-2)
  - August, 1985 (Box 253, Folder 3)
  - A -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 249, Folder 1)
  - Ba-Bn -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 249, Folder 2)
  - Bo-Bz -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 249, Folder 3)
  - C -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 249, Folder 4-5)
  - D -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 249, Folder 6)
  - E -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 249, Folder 7)
  - F -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 250, Folder 1)
  - G -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 250, Folder 2)
  - H -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 250, Folder 3)
  - I -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 250, Folder 4)
  - J -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 250, Folder 5)
  - K -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 250, Folder 6)
  - L -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 250, Folder 7-8)
  - Ma-Md -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 251, Folder 1)
  - Me-Mz -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 251, Folder 2)
  - N -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 251, Folder 3)
  - O -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 251, Folder 4-5)
  - P -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 251, Folder 6)
  - Q -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 251, Folder 7)
  - R -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 251, Folder 8-9)
  - S-Sh Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 252, Folder 1)
  - Si-Sz -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 252, Folder 2)
  - T -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 252, Folder 3)
  - U -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 252, Folder 4)
  - V -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 252, Folder 5)
  - W -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 252, Folder 6)
  - XYZ -- Alphabetical File, 1983-1984 (Box 252, Folder 7)
  - Memos from Brademas, 1981 (Box 253, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Brademas, 1984-1990 (Box 253, Folder 5)
  - Letters from Brademas, 1988-1990 (Box 253, Folder 6)
- Series XV: Publicity Photographs, 1961-2001; 1986-1998; 3.75 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 2 flat boxes
  This series consists of photographs and negatives of professors, students, and NYU locations in other countries. Countries noted in this series include the United Kingdom, Italy, France, and Afghanistan. The photographs of professors consist of portraits and candid shots. There are also several oversized photographs of President Jay Oliva. These photographs may have been used in NYU publications.
  - France, 1978, 1991 (Box 332, Folder 1, Box 336)
  - Afghanistan, undated (Box 332, Folder 2)
  - Puerto Rico, undated (Box 332, Folder 3)
  - Turkey, undated (Box 332, Folder 4)
  - North Africa, undated (Box 332, Folder 5)
  - Japan, undated (Box 332, Folder 6)
  - Denmark, 1982-1985 (Box 332, Folder 7)
  - Italy, 1982, 2001 (Box 332, Folder 8, Box 336, Folder 2)
  - Italy - Negatives, undated (Box 336, Folder 3-16)
  - New York City, undated (Box 332, Folder 9)
  - United Kingdom, 1990-1994 (Box 332, Folder 9)
  - Spain, 1961, 1968, 1978 (Box 332, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified Locations, 1972, 1978, 1991-1992, 1998 (Box 332, Folder 11)
  - Sarajevo, 1993 (Box 332, Folder 12)
  - Greece, undated (Box 332, Folder 13)
  - Prague, 1993 (Box 332, Folder 14)
  - Performances, 1991 (Box 332, Folder 15)
  - Stephen Jay Gould, 1996 (Box 332, Folder 16)
  - Portraits, 1987-2000 (Box 333, Folder 1-5, Box 334, Folder 1-4, Box 337)
  - Group Shots and Candids, 1989-1998 (Box 334, Folder 5, Box 335, Folder 1-2, Box 337, Folder 5-19)
  - Negatives, 1984, 1992-1993 (Box 335, Folder 3-4)
  - Galway Kinnell, 1983 (Box 335, Folder 5)